<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>PubTator</source><date>2020-12-04</date><key>BioC.key</key>
<document><id>24142065</id><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Common polymorphism (81Val>Ile) and rare mutations (257Arg>Ser and 335Ile>Ser) of the MC3R gene in obese Polish children and adolescents.</text><annotation id="0"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4159</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="86" length="4"/><text>MC3R</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>138</offset><text>The predisposing role to human obesity of the MC3R gene polymorphism is controversial. In this report we present the first study focused on the search for the MC3R polymorphism in the Polish population. Altogether 257 obese children and adolescents (RBMI>120) and 94 adults, who were never obese or overweight (BMI&lt;25), were studied. For all subjects the entire coding sequence was analyzed by direct DNA sequencing. One common polymorphism (81Val>Ile) and two rare mutations (257Arg>Ser and 335Ile>Ser) were identified. The common polymorphism was widely distributed in the obese and control cohorts, while the mutations were identified in four obese subjects only. In case of the 335Ile>Ser substitution a three-generation family, consisting of 20 members, was also analyzed. It was found that all carriers of the 335Ser mutation were obese, but among non-carriers obese subjects also were found. Our study suggests that the predisposing effect to obesity of the 81Ile polymorphic variant is rather unlikely. With regard to the studied rare mutations we suggest that the 335Ser allele may have a small predisposing effect.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4159</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="184" length="4"/><text>MC3R</text></annotation><annotation id="2"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4159</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="297" length="4"/><text>MC3R</text></annotation></passage></document>
</collection>
