<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>PubTator</source><date>2020-12-04</date><key>BioC.key</key>
<document><id>27860185</id><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Sildenafil attenuates hypoxic pulmonary remodelling by inhibiting bone marrow progenitor cells.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>96</offset><text>The recruitment of bone marrow (BM)-derived progenitor cells to the lung is related to pulmonary remodelling and the pathogenesis of pulmonary hypertension (PH). Although sildenafil is a known target in PH treatment, the underlying molecular mechanism is still elusive. To test the hypothesis that the therapeutic effect of sildenafil is linked to the reduced recruitment of BM-derived progenitor cells, we induced pulmonary remodelling in rats by two-week exposure to chronic hypoxia (CH, 10% oxygen), a trigger of BM-derived progenitor cells. Rats were treated with either placebo (saline) or sildenafil (1.4 mg/kg/day ip) during CH. Control rats were kept in room air (21% oxygen) with no treatment. As expected, sildenafil attenuated the CH-induced increase in right ventricular systolic pressure and right ventricular hypertrophy. However, sildenafil suppressed the CH-induced increase in c-kit(+) cells in the adventitia of pulmonary arteries. Moreover, sildenafil reduced the number of c-kit(+) cells that colocalize with tyrosine kinase receptor 2 (VEGF-R2) and CD68 (a marker for macrophages), indicating a positive effect on moderating hypoxia-induced smooth muscle cell proliferation and inflammation without affecting the pulmonary levels of hypoxia-inducible factor (HIF)-1α. Furthermore, sildenafil depressed the number of CXCR4(+) cells. Collectively, these findings indicate that the improvement in pulmonary haemodynamic by sildenafil is linked to decreased recruitment of BM-derived c-kit(+) cells in the pulmonary tissue. The attenuation of the recruitment of BM-derived c-kit(+) cells by sildenafil may provide novel therapeutic insights into the control of pulmonary remodelling.</text><annotation id="0"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">64030</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="990" length="5"/><text>c-kit</text></annotation><annotation id="1"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">64030</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1089" length="5"/><text>c-kit</text></annotation><annotation id="2"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">25589</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1125" length="26"/><text>tyrosine kinase receptor 2</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">25589</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1153" length="7"/><text>VEGF-R2</text></annotation><annotation id="4"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">287435</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1166" length="4"/><text>CD68</text></annotation><annotation id="5"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">29560</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1350" length="33"/><text>hypoxia-inducible factor (HIF)-1α</text></annotation><annotation id="6"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">60628</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1433" length="5"/><text>CXCR4</text></annotation><annotation id="7"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">64030</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1597" length="5"/><text>c-kit</text></annotation><annotation id="8"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">64030</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1686" length="5"/><text>c-kit</text></annotation></passage></document>
</collection>
