<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>PubTator</source><date>2020-12-04</date><key>BioC.key</key>
<document><id>28339057</id><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>0</offset><text>GPR143 mutations in Chinese patients with ocular albinism type 1.</text><annotation id="0"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="0" length="6"/><text>GPR143</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>66</offset><text>The aim of the present study was to evaluate mutations of the G protein-coupled receptor 143 (GPR143) gene for ocular albinism type 1 (OA1) in Chinese patients. For the current study, 8 patients with OA1 were selected from the database of ocular genetic diseases. Genomic DNA of OA1 was prepared from venous leukocytes collected from the patients. Cycle sequencing was used to analyze the exons and adjacent introns of GPR143. The variation detected was analyzed by bidirectional DNA sequencing and further evaluated in 96 controls using heteroduplex‑single strand conformational polymorphism analysis. Additionally, slit lamp photography of anterior segment, fundus photography and optical coherence tomography (OCT) were performed to identify the clinical features of OA1. In five patients with OA1, 5 GPR143 gene mutations were identified and four of them there were novel mutations. The screening rate is 62.5%, including c.333G>A (p.W111X), c.353G>A (p.G118E) (known mutation), C.658+2T>G (splice mutation), c.215_216insCGCTGC (p.71‑72insAA) and c.17T>C (p. L6P). These mutations were absent in the 96 normal controls. Only one patient with OA1 in the present study was female. Patients with OA1 often have congenital nystagmus, refractive error, severe decline of visual acuity (from 0.1 to 0.4) and foveal hypoplasia. Different degrees of pigment loss were evident in the patients' iris and retina, whereas macular structure was not identified in the OCT examination. The findings of the present study expanded the gene mutation spectrum of GPR143 and investigated the clinical phenotype of patients with OA1 in the Chinese population. Additional evidence for clinical diagnosis was provided along with differential diagnosis and genetic counseling.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="128" length="30"/><text>G protein-coupled receptor 143</text></annotation><annotation id="2"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="160" length="6"/><text>GPR143</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="485" length="6"/><text>GPR143</text></annotation><annotation id="4"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="870" length="6"/><text>GPR143</text></annotation><annotation id="5"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">4935</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="1614" length="6"/><text>GPR143</text></annotation></passage></document>
</collection>
