<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>PubTator</source><date>2020-12-04</date><key>BioC.key</key>
<document><id>28334792</id><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>0</offset><text>GWAS identifies population-specific new regulatory variants in FUT6 associated with plasma B12 concentrations in Indians.</text><annotation id="0"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2528</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="63" length="4"/><text>FUT6</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>122</offset><text>Vitamin B12 is an important cofactor in one-carbon metabolism whose dysregulation is associated with various clinical conditions. Indians have a high prevalence of B12 deficiency but little is known about the genetic determinants of circulating B12 concentrations in Indians. We performed a genome-wide association study in 1001 healthy participants in the Pune Maternal Nutrition Study (PMNS), replication studies in 3418 individuals from other Indian cohorts and by meta-analysis identified new variants, rs3760775 (P = 1.2 × 10-23) and rs78060698 (P = 8.3 × 10-17) in FUT6 to be associated with circulating B12 concentrations. Although in-silico analysis replicated both variants in Europeans, differences in the effect allele frequency, effect size and the linkage disequilibrium structure of credible set variants with the reported variants suggest population-specific characteristics in this region. We replicated previously reported variants rs602662, rs601338 in FUT2, rs3760776, rs708686 in FUT6, rs34324219 in TCN1 (all P &lt; 5 × 10-8), rs1131603 in TCN2 (P = 3.4 × 10-5), rs12780845 in CUBN (P = 3.0 × 10-3) and rs2270655 in MMAA (P = 2.0 × 10-3). Circulating B12 concentrations in the PMNS and Parthenon study showed a significant decline with increasing age (P &lt; 0.001), however, the genetic contribution to B12 concentrations remained constant. Luciferase reporter and electrophoretic-mobility shift assay for the FUT6 variant rs78060698 using HepG2 cell line demonstrated strong allele-specific promoter and enhancer activity and differential binding of HNF4α, a key regulator of expression of various fucosyltransferases. Hence, the rs78060698 variant, through regulation of fucosylation may control intestinal host-microbial interaction which could influence B12 concentrations. Our results suggest that in addition to established genetic variants, population-specific variants are important in determining plasma B12 concentrations.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2528</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="693" length="4"/><text>FUT6</text></annotation><annotation id="2"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2524</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1093" length="4"/><text>FUT2</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2528</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="1122" length="4"/><text>FUT6</text></annotation><annotation id="4"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">6947</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1142" length="4"/><text>TCN1</text></annotation><annotation id="5"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">6948</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1180" length="4"/><text>TCN2</text></annotation><annotation id="6"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">166785</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1256" length="4"/><text>MMAA</text></annotation><annotation id="7"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2528</infon><infon key="type">GENERIF</infon><location offset="1548" length="4"/><text>FUT6</text></annotation><annotation id="8"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">3172</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1689" length="5"/><text>HNF4α</text></annotation><annotation id="9"><infon key="code">222</infon><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">2528,2524</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1737" length="19"/><text>fucosyltransferases</text></annotation></passage></document>
</collection>
