<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>PubTator</source><date>2020-12-04</date><key>BioC.key</key>
<document><id>28359316</id><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Evaluation of pancreatic cancer cell migration with multiple parameters in vitro by using an optical real-time cell mobility assay device.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>139</offset><text>BACKGROUND: Migration of cancer cell correlates with distant metastasis and local invasion, which are good targets for cancer treatment. An optically accessible device "TAXIScan" was developed, which provides considerably more information regarding the cellular dynamics and less quantity of samples than do the existing methods. Here, we report the establishment of a system to analyze the nature of pancreatic cancer cells using TAXIScan and we evaluated lysophosphatidic acid (LPA)-elicited pancreatic cell migration. METHODS: Pancreatic cancer cell lines, BxPC3, PANC-1, AsPC1, and MIAPaCa-2, were analyzed for adhesion as well as migration towards LPA by TAXIScan using parameters such as velocity and directionality or for the number of migrated cells by the Boyden chamber methods. To confirm that the migration was initiated by LPA, the expression of LPA receptors and activation of intracellular signal transductions were examined by quantitative reverse transcriptase polymerase reaction and western blotting. RESULTS: Scaffold coating was necessary for the adhesion of pancreatic cancer cells, and collagen I and Matrigel were found to be good scaffolds. BxPC3 and PANC-1 cells clearly migrated towards the concentration gradient formed by injecting 1 μL LPA, which was abrogated by pre-treatment with LPA inhibitor, Ki16425 (IC50 for the directionality ≈ 1.86 μM). The LPA dependent migration was further confirmed by mRNA and protein expression of LPA receptors as well as phosphorylation of signaling molecules. LPA1 mRNA was highest among the 6 receptors, and LPA1, LPA2 and LPA3 proteins were detected in BxPC3 and PANC-1 cells. Phosphorylation of Akt (Thr308 and Ser473) and p42/44MAPK in BxPC3 and PANC-1 cells was observed after LPA stimulation, which was clearly inhibited by pre-treatment with a compound Ki16425. CONCLUSIONS: We established a novel pancreatic cancer cell migration assay system using TAXIScan. This assay device provides multiple information on migrating cells simultaneously, such as their morphology, directionality, and velocity, with a small volume of sample and can be a powerful tool for analyzing the nature of cancer cells and for identifying new factors that affect cell functions.</text><annotation id="0"><infon key="code">222</infon><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">1902,9170,23566</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="998" length="13"/><text>LPA receptors</text></annotation><annotation id="1"><infon key="code">222</infon><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">1902,9170,23566</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1600" length="13"/><text>LPA receptors</text></annotation><annotation id="2"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">1902</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1665" length="4"/><text>LPA1</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">1902</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1714" length="4"/><text>LPA1</text></annotation><annotation id="4"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">9170</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1720" length="4"/><text>LPA2</text></annotation><annotation id="5"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">23566</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1729" length="4"/><text>LPA3</text></annotation><annotation id="6"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">207</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1803" length="3"/><text>Akt</text></annotation><annotation id="7"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">5594</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1831" length="3"/><text>p42</text></annotation><annotation id="8"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">5594;50689</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1831" length="10"/><text>p42/44MAPK</text></annotation><annotation id="9"><infon key="NCBI Gene identifier">5595</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><location offset="1835" length="6"/><text>44MAPK</text></annotation></passage></document>
</collection>
